Kat Miller, PT, DPT

Corpus Christi, Texas, United States



katnmiller83@gmail.com



978-457-5744



linkedin.com/in/katnmiller

Summary

Just a hard-working, team-playing, geek-speaking technical writer turned Doctor of Physical Therapy, out to change the world one patient-centered process improvement protocol at a time!

In my careers I have...

...built outpatient programs for multiple senior living facilities from the ground up while balancing the fast paced demands of SNF setting therapy services, most months exceeding revenue budget by \$10k or more.

...lead a team of dynamic, talented therapists through the shift from RUGs to PDPM, followed closely by a massive renovation project, immediately before COVID struck, with <10% turnover as a direct result of my work to maintain a positive and transparent relationship with each team member.

...spent 8 total years in health technology consulting and software development. I spent 4.5 years in software product development as a technical writer for several toolboxes and products of varying complexity, and have spent 3.5 years as an informal consultant for EMR software as an end user and pilot tester.

Currently in process of obtaining Disciplined Agile Scrum Master (DASM) Certification and earning my MBA with Healthcare Administration emphasis, as well as Certified Associate in Project Management.

Experience



Director Of Rehabilitation

Brookdale

Nov 2018 - Present (3 years 7 months +)

- * Provide vision, direction, and leadership in developing and executing SNF and outpatient programs for CCRC therapy services to a cross-functional team
- * Develop and manage outpatient program serving all levels of care within community, increasing caseload by >500% through strategic marketing, community engagement, and client experience assessment, resulting in more than \$10k revenue over budget most months
- * Facilitated excellent therapy services across all levels of care during 2 year renovation project including over 18 months without gym access AND during COVID-19 pandemic, including providing care under unique and fluctuating circumstances
- * Successfully transitioned team from RUG based reimbursement to PDPM model while retaining top therapy talent and minimizing disruption to client experience. To date staff turnover has remained below 10% for full time staff.
- * Work with cross-functional team to ensure safest and most dignified aging in place opportunities are provided and accommodated for each individual resident

Lead Therapist/Assistant Director of Rehab

Independence Rehab

Jul 2016 - Oct 2018 (2 years 4 months)

Full time therapist for SNF and LTC patients at Haven of Yuma

Evaluate and treat long term residents for balance deficits, pain, mobility deficits, and other impairments that impact daily living and functional independence

Work with various insurances such as Medicare A, UHC, Medicaid, UFC, ALTCCS to manage patient expenses while providing optimal care and training to facilitate independence.

Use Rehab Optima for EMR and documentation

Maintain productivity >85% daily

Lead therapist in charge of maintaining compliance documents, team morale, and good working relationship with parent facility.

Performed management duties during DOR leave



Physical Therapist

RehabCare

Jul 2015 - Jul 2016 (1 year 1 month)

Evaluate and treat residents at Springbrooke Retirement Home for balance deficits, pain, mobility deficits, and other impairments that impact daily living and functional independence

Work with verious incurances such as Medicara R. Secure Harizons. Triggers to manage nations.

Work with various insurances such as Medicare B, Secure Horizons, Tricare to manage patient expenses while providing optimal care and training to facilitate independence.

Provide home health services through Kindred At Home as indicated, for residents within Springbrooke Retirement Home.

Use Smart for EMR and documentation

Maintain productivity >85% daily

Informally performed management duties during PD maternity leave including scheduling, staff conflict resolution, building caseload for all disciplines, ensuring staff access to systems, and facility communications

Developed simplified outcomes tracking methods using Excel to both decrease resources waste and increase visibility of patient outcomes over time, allowing therapists to better discern areas of function that need addressing

Developed documentation short cuts that allowed for improved "skilled language" in documentation while decreasing time required to document common treatments, deficits, and goals



Research Assistant

University of Colorado at Denver and Health Sciences Center

Sep 2012 - Jan 2015 (2 years 5 months)

Student research assistant for research within the Physical Therapy department Responsibilities include:

- * Data processing
- * Developed Matlab code to process research data
- * Developed code to explore pain processing in patients with OA of the knee

Listed as co-author on the following abstracts:

* Does Body Perception Differ Between Patients with Painful Knee Osteoarthritis and Pain-free Older Adults? (Presented at CSM 2014, primary authors Andrew Kittelson and Jennifer Stevens-Lapsley)

* Quadriceps Function Remains Asymmetrical 3-months after Total Knee Arthroplasty (Presented at ASB 2014, primary authors Joshua D. Winters, PhD, CSCS, Jennifer E. Stevens-Lapsley, PT, PhD, Donald G. Eckhoff, Cory L. Christiansen, PT, PhD)

Technical Writer and Curriculum Developer

Pegasystems

Apr 2010 - May 2012 (2 years 2 months)

- Documented new features for Customer Process Manager product suite (6 total products)
- Ensured accurate and effective training for internal personnel as well as Pega Partners
- · Work with cross-functional teams to document and develop educational materials enabling users to harness new features
- Worked with instructional experts to develop training materials and courses
- Used Word, Flare, Camtasia, and Adobe products to create lesson content
- Utilized information from subject matter experts to design online self-study courseware including videos, guizzes, and instructional exercises
- Program managed curriculum development efforts of smaller frameworks teams, giving guidance as needed



Technical Writer

MathWorks

Jan 2008 - Mar 2010 (2 years 3 months)

Achievements:

- Documented new features for eight total Matlab-based toolboxes: Graphics, 3-D Visualization, Statistics, Database, Datafeed, and Spreadsheet Link, SimBio, BioInformatics
- Consistently maintained zero known bugs for all six toolboxes, every release cycle
- · Worked with tool builders to inventory graphics used in the documentation as part of preparation for a major system infrastructure doc update
- Overhauled the PATCH function reference page to make the function more usable
- · Helped develop new reference page formats for company-wide standards
- Refactored all Graphics object property reference pages into a more user-friendly format
- Maintained a close working relationship with the developers I supported to optimize the feedback loop between development changes and documentation impact

Responsibilities:

- · Document new features on the web and in hardcopy for each release cycle
- · Address bugs and enhancement requests, reader comment forms, and other input quickly and thoroughly
- · Work with cross-functional teams to document new features for both internal and external users
- · Ensure documentation is complete and accurate, with useful examples to ensure user understanding
- Maintain User Guide and reference pages, focusing on continuous improvement

Education



Texas A&M University-Corpus Christi

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Healthcare Administration Emphasis Jan 2022 - 2023



University of Colorado School of Medicine

Doctor of Physical Therapy, Physical Therapy 2012 - 2015



University of Massachusetts Lowell

MS, Mathematics 2009 - 2010 incomplete



University of Utah

BS, Chemical Engineering 2002 - 2006 Minors in Chemistry and Mathematics

Licenses & Certifications



Certified Personal Trainer - American College of Sports Medicine



Level 3 Instructor - Spinning



CPR - American Heart Association

Issued May 2013 - Expires May 2015



Safe Strides - Kindred at Home



LSVT LSVT Big - LSVT Global, Inc. Issued Jun 2016 - Expires Jun 2022



BLS CPR - American Heart Association

Issued May 2017 - Expires May 2019

Skills

Excel • Word • Group Training • Microsoft Office • PowerPoint • Matlab • Mathematical Modeling • Research • Microsoft Word • Microsoft Excel